{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.103987, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.103989, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307a0fc6-6d44-11ea-b1ec-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b2e74-6d44-11ea-ac0a-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b2f3a-6d44-11ea-9569-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "What are the symptoms? How can you tell the difference between the novel coronavirus and a cold or influenza (flu)?", "answerText": " The symptoms are similar, including fever, cough, and shortness of breath. Some patients with novel coronavirus have had gastrointestinal problems or diarrhea. To diagnose a potential case, healthcare professionals may use a COVID-19 diagnostic test and/or run tests to rule out flu and other infections. Although there is no vaccine available to prevent COVID-19 at this time, it is important to ensure that you and your family’s vaccinations are up to date, including flu and pneumococcal (pneumonia) vaccines. This will help reduce the pressure on the healthcare system by reducing vaccine-preventable diseases. Everyone age 6 months and older should be vaccinated against flu every year.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.124366, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.124367, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b300c-6d44-11ea-a407-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b3040-6d44-11ea-baef-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b3074-6d44-11ea-8312-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Who is most at risk?", "answerText": " People who are at higher risk of getting very sick from this illness include:  Older adults; People who have serious chronic medical conditions like heart disease, diabetes, lung disease;  View the CDC website for the most up-to-date information on those at higher risk of serious illness from COVID-19.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.179301, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.179302, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b30ae-6d44-11ea-a01d-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b30e8-6d44-11ea-8dcd-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b3112-6d44-11ea-9adc-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Are people contagious before they develop symptoms?", "answerText": " There is evidence that the novel coronavirus can be spread before an individual develops symptoms. This poses a problem because people who do not know they are infected may continue to go to work, school, and other public places. People who are sick and have symptoms are more likely to stay home, which means fewer opportunities for the virus to spread from one person to another. When asymptomatic transmission occurs, infection control experts and public health officials may need to take additional measures, such as social distancing, isolating patients, or using quarantines.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.23455, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.234551, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b316c-6d44-11ea-8d93-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b319e-6d44-11ea-9542-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b31c6-6d44-11ea-9f15-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "What should people do if they think they may have been infected?", "answerText": " Individuals who think they may have been exposed to coronavirus, either through travel to an affected area or close contact with someone who has a confirmed case, should call a healthcare professional if they have any of the symptoms. It is important to call first, so that the clinic or hospital can prepare and prevent the spread of infection. To diagnose a potential case, healthcare professionals will run tests to rule out flu and other common infections.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.288952, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.288954, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b3218-6d44-11ea-8a5c-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b323e-6d44-11ea-b8ce-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b3270-6d44-11ea-9206-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "What can individuals do to protect themselves?", "answerText": " Healthy habits can help prevent the spread of coronavirus and other respiratory viruses:  Wash hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds; Avoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth; Avoid close contact with people who are sick; Stay home when you are sick; Cover your coughs and sneezes; Clean and disinfect common objects and surfaces;  Check with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) for specific guidance for travelers. There is currently no vaccine to prevent COVID-19 infection, but there are vaccines available to help prevent flu. Annual flu vaccination is recommended in the US for everyone age 6 months and older.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.373249, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.37325, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b32ac-6d44-11ea-b974-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b32de-6d44-11ea-bfb5-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b3306-6d44-11ea-8fcc-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Do face masks or surgical masks protect against novel coronavirus?", "answerText": " Surgical masks are not recommended for the general public—these masks do not prevent the person who is wearing them from inhaling respiratory viruses, they only prevent those who are already sick from further spreading germs. Spaces and gaps can form around the cheeks and edges of the mouth, making it easy for air and germs to move in and out. Proper handwashing is more effective in preventing respiratory infections. There are two circumstances in which wearing a face mask is appropriate for the general public: If you are sick, you should wear a face mask when you are around other people and before you enter a healthcare professional’s office. If you are caring for someone who is sick and is not able to wear a face mask, wear a face mask when you enter their room. Healthcare professionals sometimes wear N-95 respirators, a type of face mask that must be specially fitted. When worn properly, N-95 respirators can make breathing difficult, and they should not be worn for a long period of time.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.4152162, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.4152179, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b334c-6d44-11ea-9d4f-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b337e-6d44-11ea-a200-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b33a6-6d44-11ea-92b3-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Do we know how long coronavirus lives on surfaces? ", "answerText": " Initial reports indicate that the COVID-19 virus can live for several hours to days in aerosols and on surfaces. It is important to clean and disinfect frequently touched surfaces each day.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.4653382, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.46534, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b33d8-6d44-11ea-a478-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b340a-6d44-11ea-98b6-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b3434-6d44-11ea-97a9-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "What are the best cleaners to remove coronavirus germs?", "answerText": " It is important to clean and disinfect frequently touched surfaces on a regular basis. Detergent or soap and water can be used to clean surfaces. To disinfect, use diluted household bleach solutions, alcohol solutions with at least 70% alcohol, or common household disinfectants, which are effective in killing this virus and can be used safely. Hand hygiene is most important because hands are the primary means of transmission for this virus. There are many things that we cannot control but we can wash hands and keep them away from our faces.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.487711, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.487712, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b3464-6d44-11ea-b7f4-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b3498-6d44-11ea-bcf9-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b34be-6d44-11ea-8166-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "What is social distancing? ", "answerText": " Deliberately increasing the physical space between people to avoid spreading illness. Staying at least 6 feet away from other people lessens your chances of catching or spreading COVID-19.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.751389, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.751391, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b3506-6d44-11ea-8bcd-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b3536-6d44-11ea-b3c2-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b355e-6d44-11ea-9fe1-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Will warmer weather mean fewer cases of novel coronavirus?", "answerText": " COVID-19 is a new virus in humans, so it is too early to predict whether it will become seasonal. If it behaves like other respiratory viruses, including flu, it could abate as the weather gets warmer and become part of the usual cold and flu season. But scientists do not yet have enough information to know for certain. That’s why ongoing research to develop vaccines and antiviral drugs that are effective against coronaviruses is so important.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.810626, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.8106282, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b35a4-6d44-11ea-ae35-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b35cc-6d44-11ea-a667-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b35f4-6d44-11ea-a35f-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Should people avoid products shipped from China?", "answerText": " The virus likely would not survive such a trip. Coronaviruses may be transmitted by touching a surface, but they are more likely to be transmitted through the air. People can protect themselves through proper handwashing.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.87394, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.873942, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b364c-6d44-11ea-9fe7-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b3680-6d44-11ea-9f47-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b36a8-6d44-11ea-9746-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Why did public health authorities declare an emergency, and what does that mean?", "answerText": " US Health Secretary Alex M. Azar II declared a public health emergency on January 31, 2020 to help public health officials across the country respond to the novel coronavirus. The emergency declaration gives state and local health departments more flexibility to shift staff and resources to coronavirus response activities. CDC continues to work closely with state health departments on disease surveillance, contact tracing, and providing interim guidance for clinicians on identifying and treating coronavirus infections.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.9227788, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.9227788, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b36ee-6d44-11ea-b592-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b371e-6d44-11ea-9407-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b3748-6d44-11ea-a5ca-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "I heard that coronavirus is a pandemic. What does that mean?", "answerText": " The World Health Organization (WHO) on March 11, 2020 declared COVID-19 a pandemic. Scientists use that term to describe a new virus that emerges and spreads to multiple countries throughout the world. It means that the new virus is widespread and is spreading efficiently in those countries, but it does not tell us how severe the virus may be.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354900.968725, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354900.968726, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "307b377a-6d44-11ea-8151-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "307b37ac-6d44-11ea-9360-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "307b37d4-6d44-11ea-866d-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "How do outbreaks normally end?", "answerText": " There are several ways that an outbreak can come to an end. The Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) outbreak was controlled through close coordination between public health officials and clinicians who were able to diagnose cases, isolate infected patients, trace their contacts, and implement strong infection control policies. An outbreak can dwindle once the virus has infected most of the people who are susceptible to it, because it has fewer targets, as was the case with the Zika virus outbreaks in recent years. If COVID-19 behaves like other respiratory viruses, including flu, it could abate as the weather gets warmer and may become part of the annual cold and flu respiratory season. ", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354901.044872, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354901.044873, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfbdb4-6d44-11ea-868c-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfbe68-6d44-11ea-9269-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfbeae-6d44-11ea-979a-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Why are older adults and people with chronic health conditions at higher risk?", "answerText": " Older adults and people who have chronic medical conditions including heart disease, lung disease, diabetes, cancer, and hypertension are at higher risk for more serious COVID-19 illness and death. This is because our immune systems grow weaker as we age, which makes it more challenging for older adults to fight off infectious diseases. Chronic diseases are more common with age, can compromise the immune system, and make people more vulnerable to serious complications. Because of the rapid spread of COVID-19, the CDC recently issued a warning for people who are at the highest risk for serious illness from the virus. It is imperative older adults and others who are at high risk heed the advice of the CDC.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354901.101986, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354901.101986, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfbf62-6d44-11ea-a705-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9834bc6c-7085-11ea-bff4-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "30bfbfc6-6d44-11ea-a3e3-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "What are the symptoms of COVID-19 and how is it different from flu and allergies?", "answerText": "The main symptoms of COVID-19 , which may appear between 2 to 14 days after exposure , include : fever , cough , and difficulty breathing or shortness of breath . Not everyone with COVID-19 will experience symptoms , or they may be mild enough that they are dismissed , but they can still be contagious . These symptoms can also seem similar to flu and seasonal allergies but there are some differences .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354901.140321, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354901.140322, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfc048-6d44-11ea-897b-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfc070-6d44-11ea-a92f-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfc0a2-6d44-11ea-834d-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "When should I call a healthcare professional?", "answerText": " It is important to call a healthcare professional as soon as possible if you think you may have been exposed to COVID-19 and begin to develop symptoms. It is important to call first, so that the clinic or hospital can prepare and prevent the spread of infection.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354901.163938, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354901.163939, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfc124-6d44-11ea-a3c0-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfc158-6d44-11ea-aeeb-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfc17e-6d44-11ea-aea2-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "How do they test for COVID-19?", "answerText": " To diagnose a potential case, healthcare professionals may run tests to rule out influenza and other common infections. Not all healthcare facilities are able to test for COVID-19 at this time. The test involves swabbing the nose and throat, and taking samples of any saliva and mucus that is coughed up. They may also draw blood.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354901.197628, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354901.19763, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfc21e-6d44-11ea-8517-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfc250-6d44-11ea-be90-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfc278-6d44-11ea-b794-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "Will I have to pay for testing?\n", "answerText": " The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) is taking important steps to waive cost-sharing for COVID-19-related testing and treatment to ensure all patients who need it have access to care. Medicare and Medicare Advantage Plans will cover lab tests for COVID-19 with no out-of-pocket costs, any necessary hospital care, and telehealth services including virtual check-ins and full visits for those living in rural areas.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354901.757399, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354901.757401, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfc4e4-6d44-11ea-a120-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfc50c-6d44-11ea-a6fb-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfc53e-6d44-11ea-93a8-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "How can I best protect myself?", "answerText": " COVID-19 is thought to spread mainly between people in close contact with one another through respiratory droplets from coughs or sneezes. It may also be transmitted when you touch a surface or object with the virus on it, then touch your mouth, nose, or eyes. It is important to avoid people who may be infected. Older adults and those with underlying health conditions that can put them at increased risk should stay home to avoid being around others. Nursing homes and retirement and long-term care facilities should halt social visits. The White House advises that all individuals avoid:  Gatherings of more than 10 people; Non-essential air travel, and; Cruise ships (Note that major cruise lines have suspended trips and others are restricting passengers over the age of 70);  For older adults and adults with underlying health conditions, the CDC advises taking extra measures to put distance between yourself and others including:  Staying home whenever possible; Considering ways to get food, medicines, and essentials delivered to your home;  This is an important advisory to follow, because there is currently no vaccine available to prevent COVID-19 and no specific antiviral medication to treat it. The best way to prevent illness is to avoid being exposed to the virus. Proper handwashing is also imperative to preventing COVID-19 infection and spread. Wash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds, especially after blowing your nose, coughing, sneezing, or being in a public place. If soap and water are not available, use a hand sanitizer that contains at least 60 percent alcohol. As much as possible, avoid handshaking and touching high-traffic surfaces in public places–for example, elevator buttons, door handles, handrails, or counters. Use a tissue or your sleeve to cover your hand or finger if you must touch something. Avoid touching your face, nose, eyes, etc. Although there is no vaccine available to prevent COVID-19 at this time, you should still ensure that you and your family’s vaccinations are up to date, including influenza (flu) and pneumococcal (pneumonia) vaccines. This will help reduce the pressure on the healthcare system by reducing vaccine-preventable disease. The CDC does not recommend people who are well wear a facemask to protect themselves from COVID-19. Facemasks should be used by people who show symptoms of COVID-19 to help prevent the spread of the disease to others. The use of facemasks is also crucial for healthcare workers and caregivers who are taking care of individuals in close settings (at home or in a healthcare facility).", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354902.274202, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354902.2742028, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfc658-6d44-11ea-b565-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfc688-6d44-11ea-9fa2-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfc6b0-6d44-11ea-bf61-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "How can I prepare to be at home for an extended period of time?", "answerText": " Public health experts are warning people that it is only a matter of time before the virus appears in local communities across the US. Here are some simple ways to prepare: Ask your physician or local pharmacy if ordering your medicines online is an option. Many online pharmacies (including national chains) will fill valid prescriptions and ship them directly to your door allowing you to avoid going to the pharmacy in person. CMS is also working with private plans to waive prescription drug refill limits and to relax restrictions on home or mail delivery of prescription drugs. However, only order from a reputable online pharmacy. The United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA) warns consumers about rogue online pharmacies that claim to sell prescription medicines at deeply discounted prices. Read the FDA warning here. If you have questions, call a healthcare professional. Also, be sure you have over-the-counter medicines and medical supplies (fever reducers, tissues, hydrating beverages, etc.) to treat fever and other symptoms. Have enough basic household items and groceries on hand so you are prepared to stay at home for an extended period of time. Most major grocery chains have made it possible to order groceries online and have them delivered to your door within hours or days. Check the websites of local or national grocery stores that may allow you to select your items online and then arrange for shipping. Keep in mind, however, that many of these services are experiencing delays due to the high volume of people choosing the safety of online ordering rather than in-person shopping. This means you will need to plan ahead. If you have questions or concerns about the delivery timeline, speak to a customer service representative. If you must go out for groceries, try to find a local grocery store that offers hours just for older adults. Most of these hours are earlier in the day and offer a chance for older adults to shop without as much exposure. Remember to stay vigilant with handwashing and avoid touching your eyes, mouth, and nose since the coronavirus can remain on some surfaces for hours and in some cases, days.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354902.3262851, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354902.3262851, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfc78c-6d44-11ea-8a52-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfc7be-6d44-11ea-91de-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfc7e6-6d44-11ea-93b3-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "How can I help loved ones at risk?", "answerText": " Everyone has a role to play in reducing community spread. The same recommendations for people at risk should be adhered to by everyone to help protect the more vulnerable in our communities. Businesses, schools, and local and federal government should all work together to mitigate community spread of COVID-19 and help protect older adults and those with pre-existing medical conditions. If you are a caregiver for someone in a long-term care facility, respect their rules on who can come and go, ask about the health of the other residents frequently, and know the plan if there is an outbreak. If your loved ones live alone, check on them frequently and find out what services your local Area Agency on Aging offers.", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354902.409038, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354902.409039, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfc8d8-6d44-11ea-bfd9-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfc908-6d44-11ea-bf53-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfc930-6d44-11ea-a877-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "What should I do if I get sick?", "answerText": " If you do get sick, first call a healthcare professional. Unless you need immediate medical care, you should stay at home to avoid spreading your illness. Stay in touch with others by phone or email. You may need to ask for help from friends, family, neighbors, community health workers, and others if you become sick. Determine who can provide you with care if your caregiver gets sick. If you or a loved one needs help, contact your local public health department to connect with caregiving services. If you develop emergency warning signs for COVID-19, call 9-1-1 and get medical attention immediately. In adults, emergency warning signs include:  Difficulty breathing or shortness of breath; Persistent pain or pressure in the chest; New confusion or inability to arouse and/or; Bluish lips or face; ", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/common-questions-and-answers-about-covid-19-for-older-adults-and-people-with-chronic-health-conditions/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585354902.498204, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585354902.498208, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "30bfc980-6d44-11ea-b527-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "30bfc9a8-6d44-11ea-88e0-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "30bfc9da-6d44-11ea-a389-3af9d3ce0829", "questionText": "What are other reliable resources for the most up-to-date information?", "answerText": "  Administration for Community Living: acl.gov/COVID-19; ; United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention: coronavirus.gov; ; World Health Organization: who.int; ;   ", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585352967.264825, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585022400.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "98144646-7085-11ea-835e-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "981446a8-7085-11ea-ad8a-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "981446f8-7085-11ea-a397-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Is it safe to go to the dentist — or any other routine healthcare provider — in the near future ?", "answerText": "The current recommendation is to postpone elective dental procedures and elective surgeries , to avoid putting an extra strain on the US healthcare system . In an emergency , call 911 . If you have a specific issue that needs attention , talk with a healthcare professional who can provide advice . Routine visits should be postponed at this time .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Is it safe to go to the dentist — or any other routine healthcare provider — in the near future ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "The current recommendation is to postpone elective dental procedures and elective surgeries , to avoid putting an extra strain on the US healthcare system . In an emergency , call 911 . If you have a specific issue that needs attention , talk with a healthcare professional who can provide advice . Routine visits should be postponed at this time .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585352967.264854, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585022400.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "98144766-7085-11ea-86ab-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "981447c0-7085-11ea-9ced-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9814481a-7085-11ea-995b-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Is it dangerous to be outdoors ?", "answerText": "Going out for a walk is good exercise and psychologically beneficial . But , avoid contact with people who are sick , and maintain a 6-foot distance between others . If you are age 60 or over or have an underlying health condition such as heart disease , lung disease , or diabetes , be extra careful about being around others — either indoors or outdoors .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Is it dangerous to be outdoors ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "Going out for a walk is good exercise and psychologically beneficial . But , avoid contact with people who are sick , and maintain a 6-foot distance between others . If you are age 60 or over or have an underlying health condition such as heart disease , lung disease , or diabetes , be extra careful about being around others — either indoors or outdoors .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.nfid.org/infectious-diseases/frequently-asked-questions-about-novel-coronavirus-2019-ncov/", "sourceName": "National Foundation for Infectious Diseases", "dateScraped": 1585352967.264884, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585022400.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "98144892-7085-11ea-942b-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "981448ec-7085-11ea-bbba-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "98144946-7085-11ea-9d31-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "What needs to happen for the social separation ( distancing ) to eventually end ?", "answerText": "Local authorities are carefully tracking the occurrence of COVID-19 in each community . Once the number of cases starts to decline , federal , state , and local authorities will consider how to end social distancing and will likely do so gradually . Pay attention to public health authorities , follow the advice , and continue healthy habits like washing your hands and avoiding touching your face .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "What needs to happen for the social separation ( distancing ) to eventually end ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "Local authorities are carefully tracking the occurrence of COVID-19 in each community . Once the number of cases starts to decline , federal , state , and local authorities will consider how to end social distancing and will likely do so gradually . Pay attention to public health authorities , follow the advice , and continue healthy habits like washing your hands and avoiding touching your face .", "answerLinks": {}}}
